Welcome back.
Our little website is coming on looking super cool, but we can make it look better.
Yeah we can.
Yes.
You reckon?
Yeah.
I think we can make it look better.
You're convinced?
Yeah.
Just to add that that that.
Is that what you're going to say?
No.
Okay.
Well, whatever.
But I want to start with a little thing.
Um, we've got these cool little things and columns to look at.
How those would maybe be a little nicer center.
Now, centering is quite a handy thing just to do for whatever reason.
If you want to center a piece of text or whatever, we're going to send our stuff that's in the columns.
So remember we've got our row and that row, we've got data items which essentially are columns.
So here's our first one.
And that is a paragraph that is made up between the opening and closing P.
Now what we can do is use the center tag.
It's really quite simple.
Guess what it is.
You just type the word center and it's the center tag.
And you can then just copy that and put it in between our opening and closing peas.
So obviously what we've got to do is we've got to do that again for for each of them.
We're going to stick the center tag in.
So again you can just do center and do it.
So if you want each of them to be centered.
So there is a little, uh, cool shortcut that we can look at later that can help you make this a little
bit easier.
But at the moment we just keep one thing at a time.
So center tag opening and closing.
Right.
So let's have a look.
Uh, nipping across.
Here we go.
What should happen?
Three.
Two.
One bang.
Okay, you sort of get the idea.
Uh, they have now been centered in each of those columns, right.
So that's it's not bad, not bad, not bad.
But you know what gives it a much neater or it's just a beautiful.
But you know what would make it more beautiful of an image.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Like, see, it's like this YouTube, you know this is cool.
What do you think?
Yeah.
You've got your text, then above it we've got, um, we've got our images and.
So you've got like a the, the, the text below an image.
So if we had like a design like that.
So we had our text and our image.
So maybe you know this is a bit boring at the moment.
Needs that.
It needs to like the V the V the throb the V.
Is that the right word?
Maybe, I don't know, whatever.
You know, it just needs that little like that that.
What's the word I'm looking for V we need that like image.
That was just boring.
It's just text.
So what would be cool, Josh, is if we had like a picture of Albert Einstein and Nelson, Nelson Mandela,
Benjamin, Benjamin Franklin above each of these.
So I reckon we can make that rock.
So what are we going to do?
So we're going to have to find those images.
We're going to have to find those images.
Okay.
So that's the first thing we're going to do.
So let's go and head across to, uh, to our friend Google.
We're going to specifically go to Google Images search because that's just like the easiest place to
go and look for images.
Um, and uh, who was our first fellow that we had over there?
Albert.
Einstein.
So if we want to get an image of Albert.
What?
What you can do, uh, is a little tip here.
Rather than getting a huge, gigantic image that you is going to take a long time to load on your site
and cause all sorts of, uh, issues.
You can control multiple items here.
So when you've clicked tools, you'll see a little drop down and gives you some options.
And you can choose any size large, medium.
You can even choose an icon size, which is obviously going to be nice and small.
So let's go for that.
All right.
Uh, let's see.
Uh, where's an interesting little picture of our image?
Do you like him with his these little tongue sticking out here?
Right.
So when you find an image that you like, what you need to do is you need to get the image address where
this image is stored.
Okay.
So you right click and choose copy image.
Ah yep.
The image address.
Yeah yeah.
Image address okay.
So we're gonna need that address because that is where the image is hosted.
Your image has to be hosted somewhere.
It's very important.
So either you need to upload your image to a place where you can host it.
So for example, you could host it in Google Drive, Dropbox wherever you like or if you're paying for
some hosting.
But ultimately it needs to be at a point.
Now you could host it locally on your own website, but then it would only work on your computer.
But once you've published to the web, people can't access your your your, your local hard drive.
So it needs to be hosted online.
So anyway, we're just using these.
We're just pointing to this image that is stored on someone's website.
And we're going to nip across here.
Now what do we need to do Joshua, is what we need more rows.
Yeah I think we just put another row in.
So we're going to put a row above it.
So how many rows we got at the moment.
We got one row okay.
We got one row.
You can see it's starting there.
So we're going to put in another.
Yeah.
TR okay.
So we're ready to put in another row there.
Make a few little spaces.
So what we now need what comes next.
We're going to put in our TDs.
Yeah okay.
So we're going to put in our TDs which is going to be our data.
So we're going to essentially end up with three of these.
So we're going to have one of these for that is going to occur above each of the rows below.
So there'll be one for each one.
So okay we set that up.
So now we've got blank.
If we look at it at this stage and save that is it going to look amazing.
It's going to look like nothing you might have noticed.
It just jumped down a little bit because it is actually a blank row sitting there but nothing in it.
Right.
So what's next?
How do we insert an image?
That's what I want to know okay.
So now with the image this is where we get to what most websites have which are images.
And it's actually fairly easy.
So if we just type in R g uh and hit tab this is going to autofill the you always have to hit the tab.
Hit it.
Um, as you can see if we do this you can see the suggestion.
So IMG hit it.
Yeah it's going to have that um so easier uh to do.
Just go img click tab and you'll see it auto fills s r c equals.
And it's got this little bracket okay.
So it's waiting for something.
Now src is the source that is wants to know where is the image stored.
That's what we were saying a moment ago.
You have to inform it as to where the image is stored.
It has to be stored somewhere.
Now obviously it's going to be an online web page.
The image has to be stored online.
So at the moment the ones we are grabbing are stored online on someone's site.
So it's basically going to put that in there.
Yeah.
So now if we paste.
See it's this is the link to the image.
Okay.
So that's a link to someone's website where that image is.
And if there we go there is our tongue out.
Now just a little point.
Be very careful.
Is the source has to point to an image not to another HTML page or something.
Notice at the end here this needs to be an image, a jpeg, a png, some sort of image file.
Because if you don't do it right, you're not going to get the image.
So in fact, if we go across who we got next Nelson okay, let's go and find Nelson.
Nelson, where are you?
All right, so, um, we're still searching on icon sizes.
Which one do we want?
That one.
This one?
This one.
I'm going to use that one now, again.
Now watch closely.
Foster the I I'm doing a right click.
Now What we're doing here is I'm not copying a link address that is different.
I'm copying the image address because a link address.
Let me just show you if I copied that and just copy and paste it so you can see what it looks like is
a long thing that looks like that.
There is no dot png, not no dot jpeg.
Okay, we're not doing that.
We're copying an image address.
So I actually want the exact address where the images noticed.
There it is.
You see it finishes with a JPEG.
So that's what we want the image address.
So Josh what are we going to do now.
So um g tab and paste right.
So that's our second one.
And then we got it.
One more.
Uh, we got to find old, old Benji.
Yeah.
Ben Benjamin, where are you?
Roger.
Oh.
Let's see.
This one looks all right, as you'll see.
I was on the side there because we have chosen a specific icon size.
All of them will be 256 by 256.
So you'll notice now just save this save image.
Copy the address.
Um, we save that, we put it in here.
Stick him in stick.
Benji.
Benji, go.
There you go.
And Benji is in.
Now, you notice when we refresh our tab, you'll see that all the same size.
As if we didn't have them like that, there wouldn't be the same size.
Yeah, so, I mean, that can make it look a little bit ugly.
So just you says, you know, we we specifically chose icon sizes, which made it nice.
Yeah.
Let me just show you if I had to just go say large, um, I'm going to find some other size for good
old Benji or.
Aw.
And there's Benji over there.
Uh, now, you see, that's way bigger.
That's two, seven, four four by one eight, nine.
Now, I actually wouldn't want an image that big that's going to really make things.
That's a slightly smaller one.
But now besides the size, what's going to happen is if I had to take that image address and put that
in.
And let's replace what we've got here for for Benji with the new one.
So we're going to replace that a little bit.
Take that out and paste the new one in.
Take a look at what happens.
How beautiful is this going to be.
How beautiful is it going to be or not.
Okay.
See what's happened.
Um, that one is really big.
It's taking a long time to load.
It doesn't look nice.
It's not the same size.
So let's command Z.
That or before we do that, we have another option.
Another option.
So you want this image.
But like that's too big.
It's nice and black and white.
But you might not always get the images exactly the same size.
Yeah.
So we just go with um so you can actually specify the width of your image.
So it's going to scale your image to a certain width.
So we say width equals then in inverted commas.
Yeah.
And we'll say 266 I think that's what the other ones were.
So let's check out Benji.
Work with us.
Benji work with us.
Benji.
It's still very large to load, but, um, okay, so he is the he's the right width now, but obviously.
Yeah, the heart would be different.
Yeah.
Because if we had a square, if we had to set the height as well, he would be very squished.
You'd have a long Benji.
Yeah.
But, um, you can see it's got the same dimensions as.
Okay.
So that is looking pretty cool.
So you can alter and play with the width items of things.
So you can add that to the end and alter the width of any of these manually.
And obviously you need to fiddle with uh, the height etc...
So ideally, if you're trying to make it all look the same, you're going to have to try and find images
the same.
Or obviously you can download the images and crop them yourself.
So there we've got three of them.
We've got.
It's not looking too bad.
Yeah, yeah.
We've got our Albert and Nelson and Benjamin.
So what we've done, unbeknownst to people, we've got three two rows sitting here with three columns
controlling this.
And we've got images.
I think that's looking pretty good.
Yeah.
I mean they're starting to begin to look like a website.
I think that's actually looking like we've got our quotes.
What about our people?
I know what we need.
Just one last thing.
We just need a header at the top.
Yeah.
What do you say?
I say you say.
So what will we use?
Are we going to use the h1 h1 header?
Uh, we can say something about quotes.
Education quotes?
Yeah.
Education quotes that rock my world.
Okay.
You save that.
So we save that and here we go.
Education quotes to rock my world.
Now again, there is a little bit slower in coming up.
The reason being is slow in coming up is what?
It's because the image is really large.
Yeah, because that's also the problem with having choosing a very large image.
See.
Um, yeah.
I'm not happy with Benji.
I'm going back and changing Benji to a different type.
I'm going to say Benji, I like those.
Or you can actually even say exactly.
That's the other option.
You could choose a image that is a specific size, uh, you know, but, uh, I'm always happy with
how Benji, who was, uh, specific.
He was a nice size.
Benji didn't get too carried away, so.
I mean, he looks pretty miserable there.
Yeah, but anyway, let's keep him here.
Uh, there's a nice 256 one.
Copy the image address.
You can keep the size in if you like.
Uh, it says 266.
That's probably going to stretch him slightly.
Uh, but it's, uh, sticking in over there.
Uh, put that one.
I think that's going to be better.
And we can see how we're looking and rocking our world.
Yeah, yeah, that looks better.
There we go.
Benji.
Uh, fantastic.
So there we have it.
We can alter the size of this.
We can alter the size of all of them if we wanted them all slightly smaller.
It would be as easy as possible.
Is it an easy way?
If we say we decided we wanted all of these slightly smaller gestures, we said we want them all.
I don't know, 220 and we want to post paste that 220 like in all of them.
Uh, you know, because we want to repeat it.
So I want them all to have a width to 20.
I know we could copy paste.
Yeah.
An easy way to repeat it is let's just say, okay, we haven't got any of that.
We've starting like that.
Okay.
So we hold down command.
You'll notice there.
Okay.
So if we have you just hold down command.
Um then you see we've got two cursors.
So if you keep on clicking while you're holding command, while you click, you must be holding down
command.
So we'll give you another cursor.
Oh, we got three flashing cursors.
Yeah.
So now if we tap in, we say width.
Oh, that's very cool.
And then we can say make it 200 or 200.
Yeah.
Whatever.
We save that.
And now when we refresh you'll see it got a bit smaller.
Okay.
Right.
That's fantastic.
So that was a very cool little technique.
So if you want to have something, uh, done in multiple places, you can have three things.
You just hold down command and click in all the places that you want it to happen.
Right.
So there we go.
This should look pretty impressive.
We got a cool website coming on.
Now we've got header tags.
We've got tables and then we've got images.
You've got formatting.
You've got lists.
You've got fantastic things happening.
So well done at this stage.
You know what I think these people deserve a break.
Go out and get have a cup of coffee.
Go for a run.
I think we need to go for a run okay.
Let us go for a run.
You guys have a cup of coffee.
We'll see you back on the other side.